Guide to the Office of the Comptroller records, 1874-2002 RG0064
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Trust fund ledgers and journals, ca. 1920-1986; RG0064 Series 2; 13.5 Linear feet
  - Accounts Receivable Journal, 1964 - 1965; Includes accounts receivable entries for the fiscal year of 1964-65. Includes updated account totals for schools, institutions, and miscellaneous purchases within the university, including tuitions, fees, housing, and college budgets. Journal was originally filed as Acc. #855 and rehoused from its original binder. Accounts are organized by month, mostly in quarterly account updates, and kept in their original order as kept by the Office of the Comptroller. (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Handbooks and records, 1975-1980; RG0064 Series 3; .25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains handbooks, revisions, and memoranda. They range in date from 1975 to 1980. The materials concern George Washington University Policies and Procedures, the Planning and Budgeting Office, wages, and campus funding.
  - Comptroller's Office, 04/26/1966-09/26/1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Planning & Budgeting Office, 06/30/1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - University Policies and Procedures, 07/1976-07/10/1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Policies and procedures, general ledger funds, 1990; RG0064 Series 4; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series contains policies and procedures and general ledger funds from 1990.
  - Fiscal management, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correction, policy, and procedure statement, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Policy and procedure statement, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Policy and procedure for establishing R funds, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General ledger expenditures account definitions, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General ledger expend, account definitions, purposes, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Funds C and R
  - General ledger expend, account definitions, purposes, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Funds D and S
  - Reissue of university procurement procedures, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - List of changes, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - GWU procurement procedures, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Grants and contracts, 1971-1985; RG0064 Series 5; 16.5 Linear feet
  This series contains grants and contracts from 1971 through 1985.
- Application, loan, registrar forms, commencement materials, 1930-1939; RG0064 Series 6; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access to student records is governed by the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which protects the privacy of student education records. Student records are closed for 100 years from date of record creation.
  This series contains application, loan, registrar forms, and commencement materials from the 1930s.
- Quarterly appraisal of the university's securities, 1961-1962; RG0064 Series 7; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains quarterly appraisals of the university's securities from 1961 and 1962.
- University Budget, 1990-2002; RG0064 Series 8; 1 Linear foot (Box 2, Box 1)
  This series contains financial schedules, and range in date from 1876-2002.
  - Computer Center--Advisory Council on Academic Computing, 1989-1990, 01/04/1989-08/29/1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Computer Center--Computer Information and Resource Center (CIRC), 02/1987-09/1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Computer Center--Policies and Procedures, 07/15/1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Computer Center - Publications Review of Present Data Processing Operations, Applications, and Management, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Information Systems And Services (ISS), 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Real Estate Transactions--College Hill (R.E. & Col. Title Ins. Co. R. E. 124), 1820-11/07/1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Real Estate Transactions--College Hill (R.E. & Col. Title Ins. Co. R. E. 1,790), 04/27/1883-05/01/1883 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Real Estate Transactions--College Hill (Transfer Of Title: Columbia Title Co. Records), 05/16/1821-03/15/1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Treasurer's Office, 10/31/1938-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Treasurer's Office--Planning And Construction--Master Plan, 01/1967-03/04/1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - University Budget, 10/09/1952-02/06/2002 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - University Budget Fiscal Planning and Budgeting Committee, 2000, 08/25/2000-09/2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - University Budget Operating and Capital Budgets, 1993-1994, 05/03/1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - University Budget Operating and Capital Budgets, 2001-2002, 05/26/2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - University Budget Operating and Capital Budgets, 2002-2003, 05/18/2001 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - University Budget Operating and Capital Budgets, 2003-2004, 05/06/2002 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - University Budget Operating and Capital Budgets, 2004-2005, 05/15/2003 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Vice-President and Treasurer, Office of the Herzog, Henry W., 07/01/1931-03/06/1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Vice-President and Treasurer, Office of the Services Provided by the Office, 1974-02/08/2002 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Real Estate current records [1/4], 1981-1989; Series 8 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Real Estate current records [2/4], 1981-1989; Series 8 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Real Estate current records [3/4], 1981-1989; Series 8 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Real Estate current records [4/4], 1981-1989; Series 8 (Box 2, Folder 4)